You still do the head residence here.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.  The foundation,
in fact, is inside the factory.  These are
two things that mix together, as you
can see.  Here is the Lange, where
artists rest and discuss.  Over there
are the kitchens, there is all
the hospitality for the artists, the
residences and these are two
very moving and
incredibly timely works, always by Yoko: this is
her globe that has only borders.
geographically, like ping pong players,
they are no longer opponents because playing
ping pong with two rackets like that is not
possible.  Then there is the
factory artwork.  The factory also becomes a work of
art with a frame.  We look at
documents from all over the
world.  We're talking about magazines ranging from
Japan to Paraguay, from Argentina
to the former Soviet bloc.  It holds one of
the most important collections of
Fluxus and concrete, visual and
sound poetry.  In Europe, perhaps in the world,
everything that exists in the foundation can
be summed up in the concept of
intermedia which is represented in this
map drawn here in the Bonotto house in
1995 by Kiggins, that is to say that art
is no longer attributable to a
specific media, a specific aesthetic category,
painting, sculpture, but in those years
a breakthrough occurs between the various
categories, but new formats are created
such as video and performance.
This is the first edition made in
1912 of the Futurist Manifesto.  This is
a book that will change art.  The word
is no longer tied only to the
written meaning, but for the first time the word
is seen, it becomes graphic.